<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abstracts on Gorislab</title>
    <link>/abstracts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abstracts on Gorislab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/abstracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/goris2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/goris2013/</guid>
      <description>Goris, R. L. T., Putzeys, T., Wagemans, J., &amp;amp; Wichmann, F. A. (2013). A neural population model for visual pattern detection. Psychological Review, 120, 472–496.
Pattern detection is the bedrock of modern vision science. Nearly half a century ago, psychophysicists advocated a quantitative theoretical framework that connected visual pattern detection with its neurophysiological underpinnings. In this theory, neurons in primary visual cortex constitute linear and independent visual channels whose output is linked to choice behavior in detection tasks via simple read-out mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/goris2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/goris2014/</guid>
      <description>Goris, R. L. T., Movshon, J. A., &amp;amp; Simoncelli, E. P. (2014). Partitioning neuronal variability. Nature Neuroscience, 17, 858–865. Responses of sensory neurons differ across repeated measurements. This variability is usually treated as stochasticity arising within neurons or neural circuits. However, some portion of the variability arises from fluctuations in excitability due to factors that are not purely sensory, such as arousal, attention and adaptation. To isolate these fluctuations, we developed a model in which spikes are generated by a Poisson process whose rate is the product of a drive that is sensory in origin and a gain summarizing stimulus-independent modulatory influences on excitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/goris2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/goris2015/</guid>
      <description>Goris, R. L. T., Simoncelli, E. P., &amp;amp; Movshon, J. A. (2015). Origin and function of tuning diversity in macaque visual cortex. Neuron, 88, 819–831. Neurons in visual cortex vary in their orientation selectivity. We measured responses of V1 and V2 cells to orientation mixtures and fit them with a model whose stimulus selectivity arises from the combined effects of filtering, suppression, and response nonlinearity. The model explains the diversity of orientation selectivity with neuron-to-neuron variability in all three mechanisms, of which variability in the orientation bandwidth of linear filtering is the most important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/goris2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/goris2017/</guid>
      <description>Goris, R. L. T., Ziemba, C. M., Stine, G. M., Simoncelli, E. P., &amp;amp; Movshon, J. A. (2017). Dissociation of choice formation and choice-correlated activity in macaque visual cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 37, 5195–5203. Responses of individual task-relevant sensory neurons can predict monkeys&amp;rsquo; trial-by-trial choices in perceptual decision-making tasks. Choice-correlated activity has been interpreted as evidence that the responses of these neurons are causally linked to perceptual judgments. To further test this hypothesis, we studied responses of orientation-selective neurons in V1 and V2 while two macaque monkeys performed a fine orientation discrimination task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/goris2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/goris2018/</guid>
      <description>Goris, R. L. T., Ziemba, C. M., Movshon, J. A., &amp;amp; Simoncelli, E. P. (2018). Slow gain fluctuations limit benefits of temporal integration in visual cortex. Journal of Vision, 18(8):8, 1–13. Sensory neurons represent stimulus information with sequences of action potentials that differ across repeated measurements. This variability limits the information that can be extracted from momentary observations of a neuron&amp;rsquo;s response. It is often assumed that integrating responses over time mitigates this limitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/henaff2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/henaff2019/</guid>
      <description>Henaff, O. J., Goris, R. L. T., &amp;amp; Simoncelli, E. P. (2019). Perceptual straightening of natural videos. Nature Neuroscience, 22, 984–991. Many behaviors rely on predictions derived from recent visual input, but the temporal evolution of those inputs is generally complex and difficult to extrapolate. We propose that the visual system transforms these inputs to follow straighter temporal trajectories. To test this ‘temporal straightening’ hypothesis, we develop a methodology for estimating the curvature of an internal trajectory from human perceptual judgments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/henaff2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/henaff2020/</guid>
      <description>Hénaff OJ, Boundy-Singer Z, Meding K, Ziemba CM, &amp;amp; Goris RLT (2020). Representation of visual uncertainty through neural gain variability. Nature Communications 11, 2513. Uncertainty is intrinsic to perception. Neural circuits which process sensory information must therefore also represent the reliability of this information. How they do so is a topic of debate. We propose a model of visual cortex in which average neural response strength encodes stimulus features, while cross-neuron variability in response gain encodes the uncertainty of these features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/abstracts/rabinowitz2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstracts/rabinowitz2015/</guid>
      <description>Rabinowitz, N. C., Goris, R. L. T., Cohen, M. R., &amp;amp; Simoncelli, E. P. (2015). Attention stabilizes the shared gain of V4 populations. eLife, e08998. Responses of sensory neurons represent stimulus information, but are also influenced by internal state. For example, when monkeys direct their attention to a visual stimulus, the response gain of specific subsets of neurons in visual cortex changes. Here, we develop a functional model of population activity to investigate the structure of this effect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>